Guide to the Department of Athletics, Yale University, Records Documenting Basketball
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Athletics, Yale University, records documenting basketball
1915-2007
RU 947
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
18.75
(14 boxes)
The records consist of scrapbooks, correspondence, scorecards, and reports documenting basketball at Yale.
Yale University. Dept. of Athletics
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 38-B (YRG 38-B), Records documenting specific sports at Yale.
Existence and Location of Copies
Basketball scrapbooks are available on microfilm from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no HM179. 1984-1985. 2348 frames on 4 reels, 35mm.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Department of Athletics, 2005.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are partially restricted. See inventory for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of scrapbooks, correspondence, scorecards, and reports documenting basketball at Yale.
Basketball; College sports; Scrapbooks; Yale University -- Basketball; Yale University -- Sports; Yale University. Dept. of Athletics
- Scrapbooks of the basketball team, 1915-1953; Accession 2006-A-017
  Scope and Contents
  Scrapbooks in boxes 1-4 and 6 are available on microfilm. Patrons must use HM FILM 179 instead of the originals.
  - Scrapbooks
    - 1915-1922 (Box 1, Reel 1U)
      Conditions Governing Access
    - 1922-1924 (Box 2, Reel 1U)
    - 1924-1930 (Box 1)
    - 1926-1931 (Box 3, Reel 2U)
    - 1931-1932 (Box 5)
    - 1931-1933 (Box 4, Reel 2U)
    - 1933-1934 (Box 4, Reel 2U)
    - 1934-1935 (Box 4, Reel 2U)
    - 1935-1937 (Box 6, Reel 2U)
    - 1939 (Box 5)
    - 1939-1940 (Box 6, Reel 2U)
    - 1941-1942 (Box 5)
    - 1942 (Box 7)
    - 1946-1947 (Box 7)
    - 1949 (Box 7)
    - 1949-1950 (Box 8)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 6, Reel 2U)
    - 1951-1952 (Box 8)
    - 1952-1953 (Box 8A)
- Records of the basketball team, 1937-2002; Accession 2006-A-112
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2037
  - Scorecards
    - 1942-1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1962-1970 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 1971-2001 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Women, 1982-1998 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Men, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - All American Team Selection, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Basketball Association, 1977-1988 (Box 4, Folder 7 - 8)
  - Basketball Score boxes, 1989-1992 (Box 4, Folder 9 - 11)
  - Score sheets, 1954-1967, 1981-1983 undated (Box 4, Folder 12 - 14)
  - Correspondence, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - General, 1987-1990 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Reports, 1942-1957 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - 25th Reunion of 1962 Team, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Scouting reports
    - Women, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Association articles, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Budget, 1986, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1988 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - England trip, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - General, 1982-1991 (Box 4, Folder 25 - 27)
  - Ivy League Basketball-Swim Championships, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Reports, 1987-1989, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Training schedule, undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Statistics, 1947-1953 (Box 4, Folder 29A)
  - Publications
    - Ivy League, 1984-2001 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Women
      - 1977-1990 (Box 4, Folder 32)
      - 1990-1992 (Box 4, Folder 33)
      - 1992-2002 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Men
      - Media Guides
        - 1958-1985 (Box 6, Folder 35)
        - 1986-1996 (Box 6, Folder 36)
        - 1997-2007 (Box 6, Folder 37)
      - Programs, etc., 1963-2001 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - News clippings
    - 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Freshmen, 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Varsity, 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 42)